IMAAN BINYUSUF

13 Zinnia Mansions, Stratford, E20 1FR, London | imaanbinyusufl@gmail.com | +447944462872

PROFILE

Highly interdisciplinary thinking, Senior Brand Strategist with 7+ years of marketing and leadership experience, supporting global brands to meaningfully connect with consumers and meet business objectives. Experienced in building strong data and research insights to inform marketing goals for leading brands including Nike, Unilever and Mulberry. Proven strengths in multi-stakeholder engagement, brand and content strategy development and project management in international contexts spanning the UK, EU, Brazil, and Jordan.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TikTok: Senior Brand Strategist (Creative Lab), London

July 2021 - Present

- Lead on marketing and brand strategy development for integrated and on-platform B2C campaigns across EU and UK. Core
 role includes digital content and brand strategy development, B2C campaigns, B2B industry strategy, response to brief,
 consulting on creative concepts, platform education & performance marketing
- Developed and executed creative strategy for B2C campaigns, role includes: managing strategic inputs to client's response-to-brief; strategy development for TikTok's biggest B2C campaign Nike Women's Euro 2022 campaign across 15 European markets, generating over 3.6 billion views; lower-funnel marketing strategy for UK's leading beauty and wellness retailer, generating 104+ million views, with strong ROAS results and increased in-store footfall; managing cross-functional campaign collaboration across 5+ marketing and sales functions (inc. creative, design, sales, measurement and PR); generate post-campaign analysis and measurement reports to inform learnings for clients and senior execs
- Led platform education and B2B strategy narrative activities: devised and presented the strategy planning modules for TikTok's <u>Business Creative Agency Academy</u> (1500+ currently enrolled across Europe); led B2B finance and CPG vertical narrative & strategy for user acquisition and on-platform content growth; led bespoke creative consultations and workshops for senior marketing execs from leading multinational brands inc. Unilever, Nike, Swarovski, Barclays, Mulberry, L'Oréal and more
- Directly report to Head of Strategy EU + UK and line manage 2 junior strategists. Directly generated \$28+ million (YTD) in client media spend and revenue for CLab team

Ogilvy: Global Brand Strategist (Team Unilever), London

Mar 2020 - July 2021

- Launched a Covid-19 global communication response through Dove's Masterbrand campaign, <u>Courage is Beautiful</u>, reaching a global audience of 41M which leveraged cross-channel promotions inc. TV, OOH, Social & Influencer, and PR
- Delivered digital brand strategy and media campaign for Dove's new antibacterial product range, which launched across LATAM in Q4 2020 and globally in 2021
- Analysed consumer behaviour data, competitive landscape and cultural trend to inform Dove's innovation strategy for their UK kids' cleansing product category
- Shared proposals to increase Shea Moisture's e-commerce product UK sales by mapping out consumer journeys and analysing data on core consumers' shopping behaviours

WPP: Marketing Fellow, London

Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

Selected as one of six nationwide for WPP's prestigious marketing and advertising leadership program to complete three
consulting rotations across various health communications and public relations disciplines (BCW, Sudler and Kantar) –
WPP consulting placement responsibilities included:

Kantar: Insight and Data Analyst, Epsom (WPP placement)

Oct 2019- Mar 2020

- Led competitor analysis research and brand proposition recommendations on reaching sustainability targets for a leading Scandinavian hygiene and health company
- Supported the New Business team in client pitches and proposals through research, ideation and proposal writing, winning \$285k in client work

Sudler: Account Manager, London (WPP placement)

Apr 2019 – Oct 2019

 Led the communication strategy at EASD annual congress to revive the competitiveness of a legacy diabetes drug for a pharma client, increasing overall media engagement and publication interaction by 15% compared to the previous year

Burson Cohn-Wolfe (BCW): Senior Account Executive, London (WPP placement)

Aug 2018 – Apr 2019

 Expanded the Obesity Policy Engagement Network (OPEN) for Novo Nordisk through multi-stakeholder engagements and collaborative partnerships across Europe and the Gulf region, doubling the size of the network and increasing overall investment by 29% by Q1 2019 Organised Pfizer's largest change management summit for their global vaccine division in six weeks, bringing together over 170 divisional leaders

Third Bridge Group Limited: Analyst, London

Jan 2018 - Jul 2018

• Conducting primary investment research for an international client portfolio of 15+ hedge funds, private equity and consulting clients across various industries, including FMCG, oil and gas, generating \$5.8M in investments

Pills and Policies: Founder and Editor, London

Jul 2015 – Jan 2018

- Founded an online platform engaging young people in Politics and Public Health by leading a team of 4 in marketing, content creation, social media management and submissions
- Produced and edited articles and videos on topical issues, including a short documentary on the Junior Doctor Contract that reached over 10,000 people on Facebook and later featured on Huffington Post

United Nations: Sub-regional Response Facility (SRF) Intern, Jordan

Jul 2017 - Sept 2017

- Monitored progress on the Regional Refugee and Resilience Plan (3RP) for Syria and five neighbouring countries (Jordan, Egypt, Lebanon, Iraq and Turkey), focusing on areas including livelihoods and social cohesion for Syrian refugees and host communities
- Edited and produced 3RP policy reports, including writing Forewords on behalf of the Director of the UNDP Regional Bureau for Arab states

UK Department of Health: Policy Communications Intern, London

Jul - Aug 2016

- Analysed and documented national media responses to UK health policies for the Secretary of State's monthly government presentation
- Produced a report reviewing the Internal Communication Channels across six governmental departments, including the Cabinet Office

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Advisory Board Member, Home Girls Unite (Non-profit)

Jan 2021 - Present

- Selected as one of 8 advisory board members for a non-profit enterprise focused on providing safe and educational spaces for eldest daughters from immigrant households
- Advised on content strategy, funding proposal writing, PR outreach and partnership to grow further the Home Girls Unite international community (5,700+ followers)

WPP Leadership Summit 2020, Touffou France

Jul 2019 – Jan 2020

- Led team of 5 to win a pitch for a client addressing period poverty in Kenya, also winning the individual MVP award (as
 voted by senior WPP leaders and client representatives), resulting in an all-expenses paid trip to Kenya to visit the client's
 local centre and see their work on the ground
- Resulted in completing the WPP Fellowship earlier than expected by landing a role at Ogilvy

Research Advisor, UK Parliament Artificial Intelligence Steering Committee

Sep 2018 – Feb 2019

• Collaborated on a <u>written evidence</u> on equity in artificial intelligence with Harvard researchers to inform parliament debate at the UK AI steering committee

Youth Leader and Delegate at Wilton Park Policy Forum, UK Foreign Common Office

Jan-Mar 2016

• Selected as one of 50 global future leaders to debate key policy issues, hosted by the Foreign Common Office's executive agency, Wilton Park, a world leading centres for discussion of key international policy

EDUCATION

University of Oxford, New College

Oct 2014 - Jun 2017

Bachelor of Arts, Human Sciences, 2:1 (Hons) - dissertation <u>published and informed</u> UK parliament's AI steering committee

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- IT skills: Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Suites, Google Analytics, SQL, and Tableau
- Interests: Social Impact and Volunteering; <u>TikTok BLark</u> (D&I initiative); Bouldering; Entrepreneurship; <u>Public Speaking</u>